Bad things happen everywhere.
Escape from Tomorrow is a horror, fantasy, comedy film directed by Randy Moore.
In a world of fake castles and anthropomorphic rodents, an epic battle begins when an unemployed
father's sanity is challenged by a chance encounter with two underage girls on holiday.
Jim, played by Roy Abramsohn.
Emily, played by Elena Schuber.
Sara, played by Katelynn Rodriguez.
Elliot, played by Jack Dalton.
Sophie, played by Danielle Safady.
Isabelle, played by Annet Mahendru.
Escape from Tomorrow is a 2013 American independent horror film written
and directed by Randy Moore in his directorial debut.
It tells the story of an unemployed father having increasingly bizarre experiences and
disturbing visions on the last day of a family vacation at the Walt Disney World Resort.
It premiered in January at the 2013 Sundance Film Festival and was later a personal selection
of Roger Ebert, shown at his 15th annual film festival in Champaign, Illinois.
The film was a 2012 official selection of the PollyGrind Film Festival, but at the time
filmmakers were still working on some legal issues and asked that it not be screened.
The film drew attention, because Moore had shot most of it on location at both Walt Disney World Resort and
Disneyland Park without permission from the Walt Disney Company, owner and operator of both properties.
Due to Disney's reputation of being protective of its intellectual property, the cast and crew used guerrilla filmmaking techniques to avoid attracting
attention, such as keeping their scripts on their phones and shooting on handheld video cameras similar to those used by park visitors.
After principal photography was complete, Moore was so determined to keep the
film a secret from Disney that he edited it in South Korea.
Sundance similarly declined to discuss the film in detail before it was shown.
It has been called "the ultimate guerrilla film".
Rather than suppressing the film as Moore anticipated
would happen, Disney did not respond.
It has been compared to the work of Roman Polanski and David Lynch.
Although many who saw it at the Sundance Film Festival expressed strong doubts that the film would be shown to a wider audience due to the legal
issues involved and the negative depiction of the parks, the Walt Disney Company did not prevent the film from being released.
At the time of its premiere, Disney stated that it was "aware" of the film; since then the online
supplement to Disney A to Z: The Official Encyclopedia has included an entry for the film.
It was released simultaneously to theaters and video on-demand on October 11,
2013, through Producers Distribution Agency, a Cinetic Media company.
It has received mixed to negative reviews, praising its visuals and
ambitious production, but criticizing its execution.
The tone is lighthearted and dark and emotional.